Xudong Liu

http://www.cs.uky.edu/ \sim liu/ • liu@cs.uky.edu • (859)536-8492

Research Interests

My research focuses on exciting topics in artificial intelligence and social science, including preferences (i.e., preference modeling, learning and reasoning), data-driven and computational social science, knowledge representation and reasoning, decision theory, data mining, and machine learning.

Education

University of Kentucky

USA

Doctor of Philosophy, computer science GPA:4.00/4.00

Aug. 2010 – May 2016 Advisor: Dr. Miroslaw Truszczynski

• Courses: Modern Operating Systems, Numerical Analysis, Algorithm Design, Distributed Operating System, Satisfiability and Equivalence Checking, Database Systems, Computer Networks, Networks Security, Preferences in AI and Decision Theory, Principles of Constraint Satisfaction, Comparative Decision Making, Preparing Future Faculty, and Grant Writing.

Harbin Institute of Technology

China

Bachelor of Engineering, software engineering GPA:3.56/4.00

Aug. 2006 – Jul. 2010 Advisor: Prof. Yushan Sun

Employment

Tenure-Track Assistant Professor Computing and Information Sciences

University of North Florida, USA

Aug. 2016 –

R&D Intern

Palo Alto Research Center (PARC), USA

Supervisor: Dr. Christian Fritz

Jun. 2015 - Aug. 2015

• Conducted research on and developed system modules for representing and reasoning about user constraints and preferences in trip planning.

Graduate Research Assistant

University of Kentucky, USA

Advisor: Dr. Miroslaw Truszczynski

 $Aug. \ 2010 - May \ 2015$

• Conducted research on logic-based knowledge representation formalisms, studied and built tools for representing and reasoning about constraints and preferences in artificial intelligence.

Graduate Teaching Assistant

University of Kentucky, USA

Advisors: Dr. Truszczynski, Dr. Pike and Dr. Moore

Aug. 2010 - May 2015

- CS215 Introduction to Program Design and Problem Solving: leading lab sessions, grading assignments, preparing exam questions and solutions, and holding office hours.
- CS375 Logic and Theory of Computing: grading assignments, preparing assignment solutions, and holding office hours.
- CS463G Introduction to Artificial Intelligence: guest instructor, on knowledge representation and reasoning, e.g., propositional logic, and first-order logic.

Undergraduate Teaching Assistant

Harbin Institute of Technology, China

Advisor: Prof. Yushan Sun

Aug. 2008 – May 2010

• Compilers and J2EE, including leading lab sessions and grading assignments.

Undergraduate Intern

Information Security Lab, Harbin Institute of Technology, China

Advisor: Prof. Yushan Sun

Aug. $2009 - May\ 2010$

• Used PHP, MySQL and Apache Tomcat to implement modules of a management system.

Professional Services

Student member: Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence (AAAI) Student volunteer: 29th AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI-15)

Program committee: IJCAI-16, IJCAI-13 Paper reviewer: JAIR, AAAI-14, ISAIM-14

Local arrangement committee: ADT-15, LPNMR-15, ICLP-11, NonMon@30-10

Page 1 of 3

Publications

Dissertation:

• Xudong Liu. Modeling, Learning and Reasoning about Preference Trees over Combinatorial Domains. In Theses and Dissertations—Computer Science, Paper 43, 2016. ProQuest/UMI, Ann Arbor, MI

Conferences:

- 1. **Xudong Liu**. *Modeling, Learning and Reasoning with Qualitative Preferences*. In Proceedings of the 4th International Conference on Algorithmic Decision Theory (ADT), volume 9346, pages 587-592, 2015. Springer
- 2. **Xudong Liu** and Miroslaw Truszczynski. Reasoning with Preference Trees over Combinatorial Domains. In Proceedings of the 4th International Conference on Algorithmic Decision Theory (ADT), volume 9346, pages 19-34, 2015. Springer
- 3. **Xudong Liu** and Miroslaw Truszczynski. *Learning Partial Lexicographic Preference Trees over Combinatorial Domains*. In Proceedings of the 29th AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), pages 1539-1545, 2015. AAAI Press
- 4. **Xudong Liu** and Miroslaw Truszczynski. *Aggregating Conditionally Lexicographic Preferences Using Answer Set Programming Solvers*. In Proceedings of the 3rd International Conference on Algorithmic Decision Theory (ADT), volume 8176, pages 244-258, 2013. Springer
- 5. Matthew Spradling, Judy Goldsmith, **Xudong Liu**, Chandrima Dadi and Zhiyu Li. *Roles and Teams Hedonic Game*. In Proceedings of the 3rd International Conference on Algorithmic Decision Theory (ADT), volume 8176, pages 351-362, 2013. Springer

Workshops:

1. **Xudong Liu** and Miroslaw Truszczynski. *Preference Trees: A Language for Representing and Reasoning about Qualitative Preferences*. In Proceedings of the 8th AAAI Multidisciplinary Workshop on Advances in Preference Handling (MPREF), pages 55-60, 2014. AAAI Press

Abstract:

1. **Xudong Liu**. Aggregating Lexicographic Preference Trees Using Answer Set Programming: Extended Abstract. In 23rd International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence Doctoral Consortium (IJCAI DC), 2013.

Technical Talks

- 1. Personalization in Trip Planning. Oral. At the Keeping Current Seminar, Department of Computer Science, University of Kentucky, 2015.
- 2. Preference and Social Choice over Combinatorial Domains. Oral. At the 1st ADT/LPNMR Doctoral Consortium (ADT/LPNMR-DC-15), Lexington, Kentucky, USA, 2015.
- 3. Modeling, Learning and Reasoning with Qualitative Preferences. Poster. At the 1st ADT/LPNMR Doctoral Consortium (ADT/LPNMR-DC-15), Lexington, Kentucky, USA, 2015.
- 4. Reasoning with Preference Trees over Combinatorial Domains. Oral. At the 4th International Conference on Algorithmic Decision Theory (ADT-15), Lexington, Kentucky, USA, 2015.
- 5. On Personalizability and Extensibility of Multi-Modal Trip Planning. Oral. At Dialog, Palo Alto Research Center, Palo Alto, California, USA, 2015.
- 6. Constraints and Preferences in Multi-modal Trip Planning. Poster. At the PARC Summer Intern Poster Session, Palo Alto Research Center, Palo Alto, California, USA, 2015.
- 7. Learning Partial Lexicographic Preference Trees over Combinatorial Domains. Oral (ratio: 12%=238/1991). At the 29th AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI-15), Austin, Texas, USA, 2015.
- 8. Preference Trees: A Language for Representing and Reasoning about Qualitative Preferences. Oral. At the 8th Multidisciplinary Workshop on Advances in Preference Handling (MPREF-14), Quebec City, Canada, 2014.

Page 2 of 3

- 9. Aggregating Conditionally Lexicographic Preferences Using Answer Set Programming Solvers. Oral. At the 3rd International Conference on Algorithmic Decision Theory (ADT-13), Universite lebre de Bruxelles, Belgium, 2013.
- 10. Reasoning About Lexicographic Preferences Over Combinatorial Domains. At the Keeping Current Seminar, Department of Computer Science, University of Kentucky, 2013.
- 11. Roles and Teams Hedonic Game. Oral. At the 7th Multidisciplinary Workshop on Advances in Preference Handling (MPREF-13), Tsinghua University, Beijing, China, 2013.
- 12. Aggregating Conditionally Lexicographic Preferences Using Answer Set Programming Solvers. Oral. At the 7th Multidisciplinary Workshop on Advances in Preference Handling (MPREF-13), Tsinghua University, Beijing, China, 2013.
- 13. Aggregating Lexicographic Preference Trees Using Answer Set Programming: Extended Abstract. Poster. At the 23rd International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence Doctoral Consortium (IJCAI-DC-13), Tsinghua University, Beijing, China, 2013.
- 14. Answer Set Programming using Gringo/Clasp. Oral. At the Keeping Current Seminar, Department of Computer Science, University of Kentucky, 2011.

Honors and Awards

Fall 2015 - Spring 2016
Fall 2014 - Spring 2015, Fall 2012 - Spring 2013
for AAAI-15
Jan. 2015
Jan. 2015
Dec. 2014
Oct. 2014
Jul. 2013 - Jun. 2014
Assistant 2013
Aug. 2013
Aug. 2013
Fall 2010 - Spring 2013
Aug. 2010 - May 2013
for IJCAI-13, ADT-13, AAAI-14
Fall 2008
Fall 2006 - Spring 2010

Technical Skills

Programming languages: C/C++, C#, Java, Matlab, Python, Perl, SQL, PHP, HTML System and software: Linux/Macintosh/Windows, Qt, Git, Answer Set Programming tools, Microsoft Visual Studio, Eclipse, MySql, Microsoft SQL Server

References

Dr. Miroslaw Truszczynski

Professor Department of Computer Science University of Kentucky 329 Rose Street Lexington, KY 40506 USA

Office Phone: (859) 257-6738 Email: mirek@cs.engr.uky.edu